Searching:
	1.Linear Search
	2.Binary Search
Linear Search:
	This algorithm will perform a sequential search of item in the given array. Every element is checked from start to end and if a match is found, 
	the index of matched element will be returned; otherwise, -1 will be returned.
	Time complexity:O(N)-compared with only once with input.
	Space complexity:Time taken to search elements keep increasing as the number of elements are increased.
	When use in real world:At Study Hour.

Binary Search:
	This algorithm works only on sorted sets of elements. So if the given array is not sorted then we need to sort it before applying Binary search.
	This algorithm searches a sorted array by repeatedly dividing the search interval in half. Begin with an interval covering the whole array. 
	If the value of the search key is less than the item in the middle of the interval, narrow the interval to the lower half.
	Otherwise narrow it to the upper half. Repeatedly check until the value is found or the interval is empty.if found return the index of matched element , else return -1.
	Time Complexity: O(LogN).
	Space complexity: O(1).

	Linear search performs equality comparisons whereas Binary search performs ordering comparisons


Sorting Techniques:
	A sorting algorithm is an algorithm that puts elements of a list in a certain order.
	The most-used orders are numerical order and lexicographical order(alphabetical order).
	Sorting algorithms are classified by:
	Computational complexity in terms of the size of the list (n).
	Memory usage
	Recursion
	Stability
	General method: insertion, exchange, selection, merging, etc.
types are:
	selection sort,insertion sort,heap sort,merge sort,quiick sort,bubble sort,radix sort,bucket sort
selection sort:
	Selection sort is an algorithm of sorting an array where it loop from the start of the loop, and check through other elements to find the minimum value. After the end of the first iteration, 
	the minimum value is swapped with the current element. The iteration then continues from the 2nd element and so on.
	Time Complexity: O(n2) as there are two nested loops.

Insertion Sort:
	The Insertion sort algorithm views the data in two halves.
 	The left half of sorted elements and the right half of elements to be sorted.
 	In each iteration, one element from the right half is taken and added to the left half so that the left half is still sorted.
 	Insertion sort is of order O(n2)
 Heap Sort:
	It is similar to selection sort where we first find the maximum element and place the maximum element at the end. We repeat the same process for remaining element.


Stack:
	Stack is a linear data structure which follows a particular order in which the operations are performed. The order may be LIFO(Last In First Out) or FILO(First In Last Out).	
	Insertion and Deletion operations are done from same side.
	push() function is used to insert new elements into the Stack and pop() function is used to remove an element from the stack. 
	Stack is said to be in Overflow state when it is completely full and is said to be in Underflow state if it is completely empty.
	Time complexity:
	Push Operation : O(1)
	Pop Operation : O(1)
	Basic Operations:
	1.PUSH()-add operation
	2.POP()-remove operation
	3.PEEK()-return top element
	4.isFull()-checking stack is full or not
	5.isEmpty()-checking stack is empty or not
Queue:
	Unlike stacks, a queue is open at both its ends. One end is always used to insert data (enqueue) and the other is used to remove data (dequeue). Queue follows First-In-First-Out methodology,
	 i.e., the data item stored first will be accessed first.
	Operations:
	enqueue() − add an item to the queue.
	dequeue() − remove an item from the queue.
	peek() − Gets the element at the front of the queue without removing it.
	isfull() − Checks if the queue is full.
	isempty() − Checks if the queue is empty.
	Time Complexity: O(n)
Linked List:
	Linked List is a sequence of links which contains items. Each link contains a connection to another link. Linked list is the second most-used data structure after array. 
	Following are the important terms to understand the concept of Linked List.
	Linked List contains a link element called first.
	Each link carries a data field(s) and a link field called next.
	Each link is linked with its next link using its next link.
	Last link carries a link as null to mark the end of the list.
	
	Types of Linked List:
	Simple Linked List − Item navigation is forward only.
	Doubly Linked List − Items can be navigated forward and backward.
	Circular Linked List − Last item contains link of the first element as next and the first element has a link to the last element as previous.
	Basic Operations:
	Insertion − Adds an element at the beginning of the list.
	Deletion − Deletes an element at the beginning of the list.
	Display − Displays the complete list.
	Search − Searches an element using the given key.
	Delete − Deletes an element using the given key.
	Time Complexity:O(n).
Tree:
	Tree is a hierarchical data structure which stores the information naturally in the form of hierarchy style.
	It is a non-linear data structure compared to arrays, linked lists, stack and queue.
	It represents the nodes connected by edges.
	Types of trees:
	1.Binary tree
	2.Avl tree
	3.Binary Search tree
Graphs:
	A Graph consists of a finite set of vertices(or nodes) and set of Edges which connect a pair of nodes.
	Graphs are used to represent networks. The networks may include paths in a city or telephone network or circuit network. Graphs are also used in social networks like linkedIn, Facebook.
	For example, in Facebook, each person is represented with a vertex(or node). Each node is a structure and contains information like person id, name, gender, locale etc.